KALEN WALLIN

+1 (308) 882-8850 | kalenwallin1@gmail.com

kalenwallin.com | linkedin.com/in/kalenwallin/ | github.com/kalenwallin

As a recent college graduate, I have little full-time experience. However, I've completed a wide range of personal projects from office software to websites to video games as well as internships that all showcase my ability to learn effectively. Take a chance on me and I'll show you how I can learn to be an effective employee for your team.

EDUCATION

University of Nebraska-Lincoln | Lincoln, NE | Aug 2019 - Aug 2023 | GPA: 3.96/4.00

- Graduated with Honors and Highest Distinction in Computer Science with a minor in Mathematics.
- Developed Minieval with a team of six students in the Game Development club.

Reykjavik University | Reykjavik, Iceland | Jan 2022 – Apr 2022 | GPA: 4.0/4.0

• Studied Web Programming and Game Engineering Architecture abroad.

Chase County High School | Imperial, NE | Aug 2015 - May 2019 | GPA: 4.0/4.0

- Valedictorian of the 2019 Class
- President of Future Business Leaders of America and national qualifier in Cyber Security
- State qualifier in Cross Country and Track and Field

WORK EXPERIENCE

Python Programmer | Wallin Farms | Part-Time | Imperial, NE | Aug 2023 - Present

• Developed an OCR-based Python program to convert images of corn tickets into structured Excel reports, significantly reducing manual data entry time for employees.

Creative Strategist | Mystic Rhoads Productions | Part-Time | Lincoln, NE | Jun 2023 – Jun 2023

• Created social media posts, updated the WordPress website, designed graphics, and researched NPO grants.

Django Web Developer | FarmAfield | Full-Time | Lincoln, NE | May 2021 – Aug 2022

- Maintained the farmafield.com Django web app with an Agile team of 5 developers by resolving 73 Jira issues.
- Notable features added include Dark Mode, Email Preferences, Rural Energy Partners Landing page, and Notifications.
- Reduced CircleCI testing times by 50% by introducing Parallel testing.
- Worked full-time during May 2021 Aug 2021 and July 2022 Aug 2022

Teaching Assistant | University of Nebraska-Lincoln | Part-Time | Lincoln, NE | Aug 2021 – Dec 2021

- Helped students understand Software Engineering through weekly office hours.
- Graded their assignments in coordination with three other teaching assistants.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

baldorf Video Game | Senior Design Class Project | Lincoln, NE | Aug 2022 - May 2023

- Updated a Unity mobile game for Mystic Rhoads Productions with an Agile team of 6 students.
- Discussed requirements and accomplishments with the CEO weekly.
- Released Android, iOS, and WebGL builds to the CEO monthly.
- Received individual Rockstar award for placing in the top 15% of students and best team honorable mention.

Game Design: Competitive Mobile Games | Distinction and Honors Thesis | Lincoln, NE | Aug 2022 – May 2023

- Designed a competitive multiplayer game mode for baldorf based on competitive mobile games research.
- Wrote a 50-page paper on the subject and defended it in a 35-minute presentation.

Custom Website Portfolios | Lincoln, NE | Dec 2021 – Present

• Designed and developed three portfolio websites to learn web development and show-off experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient: Python | JavaScript | Diango | CSS | HTML | Git/GitHub | Microsoft Teams | VS Code

Intermediate: C# | Blazor | Unity | CircleCI | SQL

Familiarity: .NET Core | Amazon Web Services | C | C++ | Java | NodeJS | TypeScript